dvla.gov.uk 2012-12-12

# Privacy and Cookie Policy

This site uses cookies to help make it more useful and reliable. By using the site or by dismissing this banner you are consenting to their use. Find out more on our [cookies policy](http://www.dft.gov.uk/publications/cookies/). Accept

>> Home > Privacy and Cookie Policy

Last Updated: 09/10/2012

This statement covers the services provided by the DVLA web site: [www.dft.gov.uk/dvla/](http://www.dft.gov.uk/dvla/). 

The Data Controller for this web site is the Department for Transport (DfT). The purpose of this statement is to inform users of the DVLA web site, which is managed by the Driver and Vehicle Licensing Agency, about the information that is collected from them when they visit this site, how this information is used, if it is disclosed and the ways in which we protect users' privacy.

## Data Protection Act 1998

The Data Protection Act 1998 establishes rights for individuals whose personal data is processed by a third party. Any organisation which processes information about living individuals is a data controller for the purposes of the Act. DfT, as data controller, is required by the Act to ensure that individual data subjects are aware of how their personal data may be used, the purpose/purposes for processing that data and to whom, if anybody, that data may be disclosed.

## What information do we collect?

Some areas of the site require you to actively submit information in order for you to benefit from specific features (such as our range of online services). You will be informed at each information collection point what information is required and what information is optional. Some of this information may be personal (information that can be uniquely identified with you, such as your full name, address, email address, phone number etc.) We only collect such information when you choose to supply it to us.

Information is also gathered without you actively providing it, through the use of cookies. This method does not collect or store personal information. Information from visitors to the DVLA web site can be collected in the following areas: 

  * comments, questions and feedback; 
  * online ordering and reporting; 
  * site usage information, using cookies. 

## Comments, questions and feedback

If you send an enquiry by e-mail to either a specific contact or a general enquiry, we will only use your personal details obtained from your enquiry to respond to your query. In some instances, it may not be possible for the DVLA to provide the information requested directly. In such circumstances we may pass your enquiry to another government department so that they can fulfil your information request. If you submit a general enquiry we will retain your contact details for the sole purpose of helping us to improve the quality of our services.

## Online ordering and reporting

Our online order form will allow you to choose which forms and leaflets you want to order and will be delivered to your selected address. The information you provide is collected for the purpose of delivering our forms and publications. 

## Site usage information

### Cookie policy

When we provide services, we want to make them easy, useful and reliable. Where services are delivered on the internet, this sometimes involves placing small amounts of information on your device, for example, computer or mobile phone. These include small files known as cookies. They cannot be used to identify you personally. 

These pieces of information are used to improve services for you through, for example: 

  * enabling a service to recognise your device so you don't have to give the same information several times during one task 
  * recognising that you may already have given a username and password so you don't need to do it for every web page requested 
  * measuring how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and there's enough capacity to ensure they are fast 

You can manage these small files yourself and learn more about them through [Internet browser cookies - what they are and how to manage them. ](http://www.direct.gov.uk/en/SiteInformation/DG_197506?CID=Central&PLA=url_mon&CRE=managing_cookies)  

### Cookies for improving service 

Google Analytics sets cookies to help us accurately estimate the number of visitors to the website and volumes of usage, e.g. website statistics. This to ensure that the service is available when you want it and fast. 

Name: _ **utma  
** Typical content: randomly generated number   
Expires: 2 years 

Name: **_utmb**   
Typical content: randomly generated number   
Expires: 30 minutes 

Name: _ **utmc**   
Typical content: randomly generated number   
Expires: when user exits browser 

Name: _ **utmz**  
Typical content: randomly generated number + info on how the site was reached (e.g. directly or via a link, organic search or paid search)   
Expires: 6 months 

For further details on the cookies set by Google Analytics, please refer to the [Google Code website](http://code.google.com/apis/analytics/docs/concepts/gaConceptsCookies.html#cookiesSet). 

### What happens when I link to another site?

DVLA contains links to other web sites, both of government departments and of other organisations. This privacy policy applies only to our site, so you should always be aware when you are moving to another site and read the privacy statement of any other site(s), which collect personal information about you. We do not pass on any personal information you have given us to any other site.

### Your Rights as a Data Subject

As a data subject, you have various rights under the Act, including a right of access to any personal data being held about you by DVLA as data controller. DVLA will supply you with details of personal data we are holding about you if you submit subject access request. Our [Release of Information](http://www.dvla.gov.uk/foi/dataprtc.aspx) section provides details of whom to contact.

## Changes to this privacy policy

If this privacy policy changes in any way, we will place an updated version on this page. Regular updating of this page ensures you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we will share it with other parties.
